<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Cris Silva</title>
    <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Cris Silva</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:46153/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Fish Feed Ingredients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/projects6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/projects6/</guid>
      <description>As a master&amp;rsquo;s student at the University of Borås, I took a course on life cycle assessment (LCA), a concept I stumbled upon when a VC firm asked about the LCA of mycelium biocomposites. I had no clue back then, but this course gave me a solid understanding of the process. Being curious and hands-on, I wanted to learn more by diving into a project. My lecturer hooked me up with an LCA project, and I juggled it alongside my other studies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building 3D Printed Molds for Mycelium Material Objects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/projects5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/projects5/</guid>
      <description>In the early phases of my mycelium biocomposite development project, I relied on plastic containers and cardboard to create molds. However, after several iterations, I realized the need for a more robust, precise, and efficient method to produce molds, especially as the demand for multiple molds within a short timeframe grew. This realization led me to explore the world of 3D printing.&#xA;A generous friend lent me an Ender 3 3D printer, which opened up a new realm of possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom-Mushroom: Mycelium Material-Based Lamp Construction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>This project is one of my favourite mycelium material art endeavours. The concept was simple yet captivating: to create a lamp that looks like a mushroom, made entirely from mycelium and sawdust. The project was conceived and completed during the 3rd Digital Naturalism Conference, held in Batticaloa, Sri Lanka.&#xA;The idea emerged from a casual discussion about the possibilities of mycelium materials. The phrase &amp;ldquo;a mushroom made from a mushroom&amp;rdquo; became the inspiration behind the project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Know-How for Mycelium-Based Materials Production in Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>Mycelium-based innovation is a fascinating area of exploration with the potential to revolutionize our approach to sustainable materials. During my time in Sri Lanka, I had the unique opportunity to establish the know-how for producing mycelium materials at a community innovation center. This project aimed to harness the remarkable capabilities of fungi to create eco-friendly alternatives to traditional materials.&#xA;Securing a reliable fungal strain was challenging, as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t obtain an established culture while in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Cinnamon Adulteration Detection Pipeline with Bar HRM Technology and Cluster Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>This project stands out as one of the most exciting and challenging experiences in my career as a research assistant at the University of Peradeniya. Through this work, I deepened my knowledge of statistics and R programming, which were crucial for our research. The project focused on the premium Ceylon cinnamon, a highly prized spice known for its exceptional quality, aroma, and taste. Unfortunately, the international market is rife with adulteration, where cheaper cinnamon varieties are mixed with Ceylon cinnamon to boost profit margins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the First Community Bio Lab in Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:46153/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:46153/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>Building something new, especially a first-of-its-kind facility, is never easy. I experienced this firsthand when I embarked on a journey to establish the first community bio lab in Sri Lanka. In 2020, during the COVID-19 pandemic, I participated in the BioSummit virtually. This event was a turning point in my life, as I connected with the co-founder of Dreamspace Academy, the only other Sri Lankan at the conference. Together, we envisioned a space where community-driven biotechnology could thrive.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
